Guide to the Charles Hobson Collection, 1985-2008 M1555
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Charles Hobson collection: design and production materials for artist's books,
1985-2008
M1555
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
25.5 Linear feet 21 boxes, 16 flat boxes, 1 oversize folder, 5 map folders
The Charles Hobson Collection contains correspondence, design notes, drawings, prints, prototypes, copper plates, etc. used in the creation and publication of artist books.
Collins, Billy
Hobson, Charles
Lopez, Barry
Mann, Charmetta
Twain, Mark, 1835-1910
Wilbur, Richard
Immediate Source of Acquisition note
The collection was given to Stanford University, Special Collections and University Archives Charles Hobson from January through September 2007, March through May 2008.
Access:
Collection is open for research.
Biography
Charles Hobson is an artist who uses pastel, monotype and other printmaking variations to construct images for books and works on paper. He often works in series, follows a historical theme, and employs the monotype as an under painting for further work with pastel, acrylic and printed texts. He began creating artist's books after working on a tribute book for a friend, Bruce Nelson, after his death in 1984. The book contained Nelson's prose in a small letterpress edition. His first artist's book was Supper in Montmartre which came out in 1985.
Chronological list of Hobson's artists' books:
1985
Supper in Montmartre
1988
Flaubert and Louise
1990
Leonardo Knows Baseball (trade edition, 1991)
1991
Degas Dancing
1991
Variations on the Word SLEEP
1994
Balzac's Coffee Pot
1994
Impromptu
1994
Parisian Encounters
1995
Breton's Dream
1995
Clouds and Dreams
1995
Magritte's Buckets
1995
Man Ray's Kiss
1996
Shipwreck Stories
1997
Fresnel's Tower
1997
Lighthouse Legends
1998
Andromeda Imagined
1999
Human Touch
1999
Writing on the Body
2000
Dancing with Amelia
2001
Anotaciones
2001
Seeing Stars
2002
Taking Off Emily Dickinson's Clothes
2003
Adam and Eve
2003
Three Kisses
2004
Poems from the Heart
2004
The Writer
2005
The Mappist
2006
The Near Woods
2006
R.O.W.
2006
red thread, two women
Scope and Contents note
The Charles Hobson Collection contains correspondence, design notes, drawings, prints, prototypes, copper plates, etc. used in the creation and publication of artist books.
It is arranged alphabetically by title into twenty nine series. The design notes folder for each book usually contains a list created by the artist of archival material for that project.
Related material:
Hobson's artist's books are housed in Stanford University's Rare Book Collection.
Centolella, Tom; Colet, Louise; DeMerritt, John; Earhart, Amelia; Evans, Kathy; Flaubert, Gustave; Levy, Harriet Lane; Muybridge, Eadweard, 1830-1904; Shaw, Alice; Artists' books; Artists' books--United States; Constellations--Artists' books; Copperplates; Longitude--Measurement-- Artists' books; Monotypes; Photogravure; Shipwrecks-- Artists' books; Typography
- Series I. Adam and Eve, 2003
  Scope and Contents note
  Extracts from the Diaries of Adam & Eve, as translated by Mark Twain, was made as a limited edition of 38 copies during the summer and fall of 2003. The images of a running man and woman created as pastel monotypes by Charles Hobson are printed as digital pigment prints and are based on the human motion studies by Eadweard Muybridge made in 1901. Additional versions of the Muybridge studies have been collaged onto each page and contain the handwriting of Mark Twain and Livy Clements from letters they exchanged in 1903. The concertina and French door structure with cut-out pages and collaged folded sheets has been designed by Charles Hobson and assembled with the assistance of Alice Shaw. John DeMerritt made the board covers and slipcase. 13 x 5 3/4 x 1 1/2 inches. 46 pages.
  - Original monotypes, pastels, photocopies, etc. Extra Epson monotype prints, mostly final; including cut outs, etc. (see also Box 2) (Flat-box 1, Folder 1-2)
  - Cutting templates (board), cutting master (photocopy) (Flat-box 1, Folder 3)
  - Templates for cutting Epson monotypes (Flat-box 1, Folder 4)
  - Printer masters: text pages (Flat-box 1, Folder 5)
  - Masters: concertina spines (Flat-box 1, Folder 6)
  - Masters: for Afterward printing (Flat-box 1, Folder 7)
  - Early trials of Muybridge Epson prints (see also Box 2) (Flat-box 1, Folder 8)
  - Concertina spine pages (some folded) (Flat-box 1, Folder 9)
  - Removed from Flat Box 1: templates, photocopies (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Paper samples (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Early trials of Muybridge Epson prints: Eve leaping: sketches, transparencies, etc. (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Prototype bindings (one with concertina spine) (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Page designs: refinement of page size and color; mock-ups (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Work notes, club paper (notebook, disbound); includes sketches, research, photocopies, correspondence, etc. (Box 2, Folder 6-7)
  - Early design alternatives: notes and mock-ups (see also Flat Box 1 and Box 3) (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Early design alternatives: mock-up cover and paper (Box 3, Folder 1)
  - Early set: posted, folded sheets (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Early set: page mock-ups (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Afterward (3 sets, one bound) (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Templates for Muybridge figures: cutting patterns: Eve top 1-5 (Flat-box 4, Folder 1)
  - Templates for Muybridge figures: cutting patterns: Adam top 1-5 (Flat-box 4, Folder 2)
  - Templates for Muybridge figures: cutting patterns: Adam bottom 6-9 (Flat-box 4, Folder 3)
  - Templates for Muybridge figures: cutting patterns: Eve bottom 6-9 (Flat-box 4, Folder 4)
- Series II. Andromeda Imagined, 1998
  Limited edition concertina book by Charles Hobson with six monoprints over star atlas drawings from 1690, six IRIS prints from mixed media drawings, and six hand-punched constellations. Edition of 30. Size: 11 x 10-1/2 x 1-1/4 inches. 32 pages.
  - Design notes: diagram for layout of pages, assembly notes, punching diagram for cut-out stars, guide for trimming concertinas, correspondence with printers, binders, and die cutting company (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Research materials and notes; includes research paper as presented to the club, 1998 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Punched star (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Prospectus and photographs (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Spine design (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Helvelius star chart 1690 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Backer's star chart, 1710 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Diagram (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Durer's star chart, 1515 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Apian's star chart, 1540 (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Farnese atlas, 400 B.C. (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Vienna mss, 1440 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Cabrarola ceiling, 1575 (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Pegasus (the magic horse) (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Big Dipper, pointer stars diagram (Box 5, Folder 15)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Perseus (the hero) (Box 5, Folder 16)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Cassiopeia (Box 5, Folder 17)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Andromeda (the daughter) (Box 5, Folder 18)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Cetus (the sea monster) (Box 5, Folder 19)
  - Star Atlas charts overlays diagram: Cepheas (the king) (Box 5, Folder 20)
  - Prototypes: cover, pages (Box 5, Folder 21)
  - Star chart designs (2 folders) (Flat-box 6, Folder 1-2)
  - Printers' camera ready art for text and Hevelius image (Flat-box 6, Folder 3)
  - Extra printed pages (no monotyping) (Flat-box 6, Folder 4)
  - Monotypes (Flat-box 6, Folder 5)
- Series III. Anotaciones, 2001
  Anotaciones is a one-paragraph fiction with sixteen footnotes by Barry Lopez. The footnotes have been printed on laser cut puzzle pieces, all contained in a cigar box with chemise. Assembling the puzzle organizes the footnotes in order to be read. Ink jet monotype, Color Xerox and offset litho. 8 1/2 x 6 1/4 x 2 1/2 inches (size varies from box to box.) Seven pages and a fold out version of assembled puzzle. Edition of 30.
  - Barry Lopez – Mendoza Vega: masters, photocopies, transparencies, etc. (Flat-box 6, Folder 6)
  - Tobacco plant drawings and monotypes (Flat-box 6, Folder 7)
  - Tobacco plant inkjet monotypes cover (Flat-box 6, Folder 8)
  - Tobacco plant inkjet monotypes and small trials (Flat-box 6, Folder 9)
  - Parc Office at Xerox: photocopy of photograph, landscape (Flat-box 6, Folder 10)
  - Design notes (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Book layout and design (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Pictorial background: photocopies, magazine pages, photographs, etc. (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Barry Lopez: text originals (photocopies); including correspondence with Lopez (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Barry Lopez: design correspondence (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Cigar label stamps: templates, photocopies, etc.; includes miscellaneous templates (Box 7, Folder 6-7)
  - Extra color photocopy versions (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Prospectus design (Box 7, Folder 9)
- Series IV. Balzac's Coffee Pot, 1994
  Honoré de Balzac's wry comment on the importance of coffee, together with a reproduction of his handwritten sentence and a pastel monotype by Charles Hobson of his coffee pot. Accordion format. Edition of 5. Size: 8 x 8 inches.
  - Book project: binding and cover materials: paper samples, etc. (Flat-box 6, Folder 11)
  - Book project: book masters: layout versions, matrix for page layout, etc. (Flat-box 6, Folder 12)
  - Book project: design notes: sketches, photocopy of Balzac's handwriting, etc. (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Book project: monotypes: preparatory and final versions (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Broadside project: design notes (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Broadside project: color photocopy version (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Broadside project: monotypes, various (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Broadside project: finished broadsides (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Broadside project: broadside text pages (Box 8, Folder 7)
- Series V. Breton's Dreams, 1995
  Pastel monotype by Charles Hobson with text on Mylar, mounted on black lacquer miniature ship, with small book describing relationship between Andre Breton and Admiral Sir Clowdishley Shovell. Edition of 4. Size: 16 x 12 x 5 inches.
  - Master text and design notes (see also Clouds & Dreams) (Box 8, Folder 8)
- Series VI. Clouds and Dreams, 1995
  Stacking accordion book in black linen case with photocopy reproductions of cloud images by Charles Hobson and portraits of Surrealists as Longitude Prize Seekers. One of three versions. Size: 10 x 8 x 2 1/2 inches.
  - Research and essay re: navigation (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Portrait drawings: Max Ernst (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Portrait drawings: Dali (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Portrait drawings: De Chirico (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Portrait drawings: Picasso / Miro (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Portrait drawings: Yves Tangvy (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Portrait drawings: Andrew Breton (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Portrait drawings: Man Ray (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Portrait drawings: Magritte (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Miscellaneous patterns and matrices (Box 8, Folder 18)
  - Photographs of clouds (see Flat Box #6 for color photocopies of clouds) (Box 8, Folder 19)
  - Photographs and color photocopies of clouds (Flat-box 9, Folder 11)
  - Loose patterns, art (Flat-box 9, Folder 12)
- Series VII. Dancing with Amelia, 2000
  Six short fictions and twelve IRIS prints taken from six mixed media drawings of dancing couples by Charles Hobson. The cover is constructed of laser cut boards printed with cut-out images of contrasting clouds, and the book is protected by a cloth covered chemise. Edition of 38. Size: 6 1/4 x 8 1/2 inches closed (7 feet long when extended). 36 pages.
  - Work notes (Box 8, Folder 20)
  - Early book design alternatives (Box 8, Folder 21v)
  - Early book design alternatives (Box 8, Folder 22v)
  - Early book design alternatives (Box 8, Folder 23v)
  - Cover design trials (Flat-box 9, Folder 1)
  - Cover design trials - laser cutting experiments (Flat-box 9, Folder 2)
  - Cover design trials - laser cutting experiments (Flat-box 9, Folder 3)
  - Original drawings and monotypes (Flat-box 9, Folder 4)
  - Production materials - text masters (Flat-box 9, Folder 5)
  - Production materials - registration masters (Flat-box 9, Folder 6)
  - Historical airplane design form (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - Cover design trials - preliminary cut-outs (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Amelia handwriting examples (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Die cut for cutting airplane shape (wood backed) (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Extra pages for small version (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Spine labels (Box 10, Folder 6)
  - Chemise pattern (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Sample cut-outs (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Trade edition mock-up (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Prospectus design and samples (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Extra pages (Box 10, Folder 11)
- Series VIII. Degas Dancing, 1991
  A fragmentary biography of Edgar Degas with five portrait monotypes accompanied by the writing of Degas and others marking key passages in his life. Most monotype folders include photographs, transparencies, notes, etc. Book information: easel accordion; edition of 10.
  - Design notes: various diagrams, pencil drawings, invoice, and paper samples (Box 11, Folder 1)
  - Typographic layout - alternative formats, masters, alternative papers (Box 11, Folder 2)
  - Research and early drafts of texts; including research paper entitled "Degas Lesson Book" and additional narrative entitled "Dancing Lessons" (Box 11, Folder 3)
  - Production materials and extra pages - labels (Flat-box 9, Folder 7)
  - Monotypes: young Degas; includes photocopies made in conjunction with residency at Xerox PARC Tech Museum (2000) (Flat-box 9, Folder 8)
  - Monotypes: Degas and streetcar (Flat-box 9, Folder 9)
  - Monotypes: Degas dancing (Flat-box 9, Folder 10)
  - Monotypes: Degas sitting (Flat-box 12, Folder 1)
  - Monotypes: Degas walking (Flat-box 12, Folder 2)
- Series IX. Flaubert & Louise, 1988
  Portfolio of five monotypes accompanying the exchange of letters between Gustave Flaubert and Louise Colet in the 1840s. Folders in Flat Box #12 include: early trials and drawings, photocopies, photographs, early proofs, photo etchings (not used in book), monotype variations. Book information: co-published with Limestone Press; edition of 18.
  - General background: correspondence with Limestone press, guest list for dinner party, permissions from publishers and authors (including note from Julian Barnes, 1988), invoices, expense records, prospectuses, etc. (Box 11, Folder 4)
  - Text and background: typescript for letterpress and Steegmuller translation. (Box 11, Folder 5)
  - Early trials - Five Roses: etchings, transparencies (Box 11, Folder 6)
  - Images: Rose and Pruning Shears (Flat-box 12, Folder 3)
  - Images: Chateaubriand's Grave (Flat-box 12, Folder 4)
  - Images: Louise's Flower (Flat-box 12, Folder 5)
  - Images: The Epistolary Relationship (Flat-box 12, Folder 6)
  - Images: The Last Letter (Flat-box 12, Folder 7)
  - Early trials - Flaubert's Rose: etchings, transparencies (Flat-box 12, Folder 8)
  - Early trials: etchings from life drawing (nude with window, Pradier's studio) (Flat-box 12, Folder 9)
- Series X. Fresnel's Tower, 1997
  Book information: limited edition of 38; typefaces are Cantoria and New Century Schoolbook; Hobson made the drawing for the hand colored photogravure; the photogravure was printed by Kay Bradner and Hobson. The cylinders are wrapped with hand painted Rives Lightweight paper and reproductions of monotypes of clouds by Hobson. It was assembled with the assistance of Celeste Wiedmann; John DeMerritt constructed the boxes.
  - General notes: design notes, correspondence with bookbinder, fabric samples (Box 11, Folder 7)
  - Box components: box design notes, partial matrix, label designs (Box 11, Folder 8)
  - Cover components: design notes, photocopies, transparencies, cover matrix, early cover trials and mock-ups, two trial books (cover and text block), book labels (Box 11, Folder 9)
  - Text block components: notes on text, text trials, end-sheet matrix, preliminary text version, layout with registration marks, mock-up text block with notes, reject text blocks, extra final text blocks (Box 11, Folder 10)
  - Photogravure trials: inking notes, trial proofs (17; two with notes and hand coloring) (Box 11, Folder 11)
  - Separator cards: extra materials for separator cards, design matrix, receipt, design notes, masters for text layout, extra small card (Box 11, Folder 12)
  - Related supplemental materials - limited edition print: limited edition photogravure with exhibition announcement from Dorothy Weiss Gallery. (Box 11, Folder 13)
  - Cylinder design notes; includes matrices for cylinders and warps (Flat-box 13, Folder 1)
  - Design ideas for external cylinder wraps: photocopies of various lighthouse drawings (at various sizes), copies cut out and placed on layouts with notes (Flat-box 13, Folder 2)
  - Exterior cylinder wraps: extra photocopies on painted paper, etc. (Flat-box 13, Folder 3)
  - Design notes for clouds: magazine pages, transparencies, transparency tracings, original drawings (Flat-box 13, Folder 4-7)
  - Original monotypes for clouds (cylinder interiors): night sky, high sky, low sky, ocean, etc. (Flat-box 13, Folder 8)
  - Interior cylinder wraps: extra uncut color photocopies of cloud monotypes, some mis-cuts and odd sizes (Flat-box 13, Folder 9)
- Series XI. Human Touch, 1999
  Seven reproduced drawings of hands printed on hand-painted Rives heavyweight paper. Imitation vellum overlays of words from such sources as Ecclesiastes, Buddha, Georgia O'Keeffe, et al. Book information: edition of 30, stab binding.
  - Original drawings: preliminary (Flat-box 13, Folder 10)
  - Original drawings: photocopies without text (Flat-box 13, Folder 11)
  - Original drawings: photocopies with text (Flat-box 13, Folder 12)
  - Garden layout, early text and design trials (Flat-box 13, Folder 13)
  - Binding guides (Flat-box 13, Folder 14)
  - Original India ink drawings (twenty; seven final images) (Oversize-folder 15)
  - Design notes: first version: layout details (Box 14, Folder 1)
  - Text and image for second version (Box 14, Folder 2)
  - Extra pages: images and work overlays (Box 14, Folder 3)
- Series XII. Impromptu, 1994
  A collaborative poem by Tom Centolella and Kathy Evans with six images each by Kay Bradner and Charles Hobson. Edition of 100. Photo-offset, some with original photographs tipped in.
  - Design notes: Early layouts; Image design ideas with photos and color photocopies; Final book design notes (Box 14, Folder 4)
  - Text edits: A. Early versions. B. Final versions (Box 14, Folder 5)
  - Paste up original page spreads with photos (Box 14, Folder 6)
  - Photo layouts - two page spreads with color photographs and music notation comparing Bradner and Hobson images. (Box 14, Folder 7)
  - Music notations, preliminary (5A) and final (5B) - reproduction of Chopin and Impromptu. (Box 14, Folder 8)
  - Cover and binding design (Box 14, Folder 9)
  - Prototypes - three versions of book, dummy (Box 14, Folder 10)
  - Color photographs - photographs of original monotypes and final page versions. (Box 14, Folder 11)
  - Afterward: photocopies (Box 14, Folder 12)
  - Monotypes: Old Shoes and Rug: ghost and counter-proof (Flat-box 13, Folder 15)
  - Monotypes: Pillows and Rose: ghost (Flat-box 13, Folder 16)
  - Monotypes: Straw Hat in Sun: ghost (Flat-box 13, Folder 17)
  - Monotypes: Lamp and Books: ghost (Flat-box 13, Folder 18)
  - Monotypes: Shirt on Chair: ghost and counter-proof (Flat-box 13, Folder 19)
  - Monotypes: Rose in gardens (Flat-box 13, Folder 20)
- Series XIII. Leonardo Knows Baseball, 1990
  Twenty copies of Leonardo Knows Baseball were made during the spring and summer of 1990. The five soft ground etchings were printed on BFK Rives at Stinson Beach, California on a Littlejohn Press. Fifteen copies were assembled as accordion fold books with the assistance of Alice Shaw and five copies have been prepared as portfolio versions. Completed in September 1990. A trade edition based on the limited edition was published by Chronicle Books, San Francisco, in 1991.
  - Book Design Notes: design and layout notes, registration guides, and production cost estimate (Box 17, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence and 10 trial proofs for aborted project at Limestone Press (Box 17, Folder 2)
  - Text Masters and Trials: formatting and layout proofs for the text of the book, print trials, mockup dummy book of text layout only (Box 17, Folder 3)
  - Labels: trials for cover labels on a variety of papers, proof colophon, proofs of actual cover labels; extra spine labels (Box 17, Folder 4)
  - Book Dummy: accordion book dummy made with Xerox images (Box 17, Folder 5)
  - Plate Design Notes: various newspaper and magazine clippings of baseball players in motion (Box 17, Folder 6)
  - Steelplates (Box 17, Folder 7)
  - Plate I - Batter: Soft Ground Etching Materials - transparency, actual soft ground etching drawing, 6 trial proofs with notes (Box 17, Folder 8)
  - Book Prospectus with prospectus text proof (Box 17, Folder 9)
  - Plate I - Batter: Monotype Materials - monotype inking notes; 7 photocopy trials on various painted papers; 3 monotype trials (Flat-box 16, Folder 1)
  - Plate II - Pitcher: Soft Ground Etching Materials - inking notes, registration notes, 4 trial proofs with notes, 1 trial proof on large sheet (Flat-box 16, Folder 2)
  - Plate II - Pitcher [Throwing]: Monotype Materials - photos of monotypes, 4 photocopy trials on painted paper, 5 monotype trials (3 on large sheets, 2 cut down) (Flat-box 16, Folder 3)
  - Plate III - Sun [Shadow/Fielder]: Soft ground etching Materials - inking notes, 4 trial proofs (one on large sheet), 5 trial proofs on page layout (four with text) (Flat-box 16, Folder 4)
  - Plate III - Sun: Monotype Materials - photo of monotype, photocopies, Original Drawings (sketch, original drawing, and tracing), 3 monotype trials (Flat-box 16, Folder 5)
  - Plate IV - Run Home: Soft Ground Etching Materials - inking notes, registration matrix, original drawing and photocopy, 6 trial proofs with notes, 7 additional trial proofs (one on large sheet), 4 trial proofs on page layout with text (Flat-box 16, Folder 6)
  - Plate IV - Run Home: Monotype Materials - inking notes, 3 photocopy trials on painted papers, 3 monotype trials (Flat-box 16, Folder 7)
  - Plate V - Umpire: Soft Ground Etching Materials - inking notes, transparencies, registration matrix, 5 trial proofs with notes, 1 additional trial proofs on large sheet (Flat-box 16, Folder 8)
  - Plate V - Umpire: Monotype Materials - photo of monotype, 4 photocopy trials on painted paper (one with pastel & charcoal drawing), 6 monotype trials (Flat-box 16, Folder 9)
  - Plate VI - Catch (cover for trade edition only): Monotype Materials - photo of monotype, transparencies, photocopies; Original Drawings (sketch, original drawing, and tracing); 3 photocopy trials on painted papers; 4 monotype trials (Flat-box 16, Folder 10)
- Series XIV. Lighthouse Legends, 1997
  A series of unique books created from pastel monotypes and found books, each based on a story around a dramatic time at a lighthouse. (Described in Why I Love Books, pp. 38-39.)
  - Descriptive memo detailing project; preliminary draft and final version (Box 17, Folder 10)
  - Design materials - Parting Shot: Boston Light charts; cut out shapes and references; color photocopy trials. (Flat-box 16, Folder 11)
  - Design materials - The Roar: Maninicus charts; cut-out of figure and references; color photocopies trials (Flat-box 16, Folder 12)
- Series XV. Magritte's Buckets, 1995